HBO原创连续剧
衣柜字幕组翻译制作
印度尼西亚 雅加达
2003年9月24日
我很抱歉 打搅了您的午餐
不必道歉
我快吃完了
警官先生 请容我问一句
我犯了什么事吗？
不
您当然没有
那您找对人了吗——？
您是拉特那女士
真菌学教授
工作单位 印度尼西亚大学
我们要找的正是您
印度尼西亚共和国
卫生部
拉特那女士 您可否看一看我们制好的标本？
您可能会注意到——
让她自己得出结论吧
这是线虫草真菌
载玻片上怎么还加了氯唑？
因为样本是从人体上采集到的
线虫草真菌不可能在人体内存活
如果您感到不适
就马上离开停尸间
看她的左腿底下
咬她的是人类吗？
什么时候发生的？
大概30小时前
在哪儿发生的？
城西边的一家面粉加工厂
真是理想的培养基
后来呢？
一个正常妇女 突然出现暴力行为
她攻击了四位同事 咬伤其中三人
他们把她锁在卫生间里
警察赶来后 她又试图攻击警察
警察朝她开了枪
被她咬伤的那些人怎样了？
他们被带走并进行观察
几小时后……
我们不得不按照规定 采取必要措施
处决了他们
谁咬的“她”？
我们不知道
所以 外面还有感染者
还有其他工人失踪吗？
有十四人
拉特那女士
我们请您来 是希望您能协助我们 防止事态恶化
我们需要疫苗
或者特效药
我这一生都在研究真菌
请您认真听我说
没有特效药
也没有疫苗
那我们该怎么办？
炸弹
用炸弹轰炸
轰炸这座城市……
炸死所有居民
不好意思
您能派人送我回家吗？
我想和家人待在一起
最后
生还
者
第一季
第二集
感染
Infected
翻译
叽拇啾＆疾火
艾莉·威廉姆斯
波士顿生还者
美国军校预备生肄业
校对＆后期＆监制
北落
乔尔·米勒
波士顿走私者
泰丝·瑟沃普勒斯
乔尔的搭档
早上好
Morning.
我看起来像是被感染了吗？
Do I look like I'm infected?
把你的胳膊露出来
Show us your arm.
行啊 我的伤口没恶化 不是吗？
Yeah, it's not getting any worse, is it?
如果我们现在身处外城 为什么感染者没有蜂拥而至？
If we're out in the open city, why aren't we getting swarmed?
这你别操心了
Don't worry about that.
我已经在操心了
Well, I'm gonna.
玛琳想拿这个被感染的孩子做什么？
What was Marlene doing with an infected kid?
我没被感染
I'm not infected.
在我被咬之后 她发现了我
She found me after I was bitten.
她没朝你开枪
And she didn't shoot you.
显而易见
Clearly not.
她把我关了起来 派人每天检查我的情况
She locked me up and had her guys test me every day
判断我是不是病了
to see if I was getting sick.
怎么检查你的？
Test you how?
我要尿尿
I have to pee.
他们检查你 怎么检查？
Test you, how?
他们让我数到十 还要我伸出手
They'd make me count to 10 and hold out my hand
把手稳在空中
and then keep it steady.
但是吧 我觉得最让他们感到惊异的
But, you know, I think what really impressed them
是我没变成他妈的怪物
was the fact that I didn't turn into a fucking monster.
我能走了吗？
Now can I please?
行
Fine.
去你身后的房间 随便找个角落
Back there. You can find a spot.
接着
And here.
撕几页下来
Tear out a few pages.
不会有什么坏家伙在那里等着我吧
There's not gonna be anything bad in here?
就你而已
Just you.
哦 真好笑
Oh, funny.
你的手伤了
Broken.
估计是轻微骨折 很快就好
Maybe a hairline. It'll heal fast.
他妈的一整晚她都撑过去了 乔尔
She made it through the fuckin' night, Joel.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
她迟早会变异
It's gonna happen sooner or later.
明白吗？我们离隔离墙还不算远
All right? We're still close to the wall.
我们可以把她偷渡回隔离区
We sneak her back into the QZ.
再想其他的办法拿到电池
We find a different way to get the battery.
这就是我们最好的机会了
This is our best shot.
我们把她带回隔离区 总会有人注意到她的胳膊
We take her back to the QZ, someone's gonna notice her arm,
扫描她的伤口 然后杀了她
they're gonna scan her, then they'll kill her.
那也总好过由我们动手
Well, better them then us.
别再说得好像这个孩子
You need to stop talkin' about this kid
还有一线生机似的
like she's got some kinda life in front of her.
你饿吗？
You hungry?
我们可以分你些吃的
You can share some of ours.
谢了 玛琳给我带了食物
Thanks. Marlene sent me with my own.
你吃的是鸡肉？
Is that chicken?
对
Yeah.
玛琳说这是从走私贩那里弄来的
Marlene said they get it from smugglers.
我猜不是你俩
Guess not you guys.
嘿 嘿！
Hey. Hey!
为什——
Why--
为什么玛琳这么看重你？
why are you so important to Marlene?
别撒谎 不然我们就带你回去
And don't lie to me or we'll take you back.
你们把我带回去 那就拿不到电池了
You take me back, you don't get your battery.
你听到我们说话了吧？
You heard that?
那你一定也听到他想要开枪毙了你
Then you must've heard that he wants to shoot you.
我以对待成年人的方式来和你说话
I'm gonna talk to you like you're an adult.
行吗？
Okay?
乔尔和我不是什么好人
Joel and I aren't good people.
我们接这个活 是为了自己
We're doin' this for us
因为 很明显 你对某些人有价值
because, apparently, you're worth something.
但是 我们如果不知道你是怎么回事 就没办法弄清你的价值
But we don't know what you're worth if we don't know what we have.
所以 来回答我的问题
So answer my question.
她不让我告诉别人
She told me not to tell anybody,
我现在是第一次跟其他人——
and now I'm telling the first people that I--
在西边某个地方 有个火萤基地
There's a Firefly base camp somewhere out west,
他们有医生
with doctors.
在研究解药
They're working on a cure.
我也听过这些传闻
I've heard this before.
不管我身上发生了什么 那都是找到疫苗的关键
And whatever happened to me, is the key to finding the vaccine.
仅仅如此吗？
That's what this is?
这话我们听过不下百万次了
We've heard this a million times.
疫苗 灵丹妙药 没一个有用的 都一个样
Vaccines, miracle cures. None of it works. Ever.
操你妈 又不是我想提的
Fuck you, man. I didn't ask for this.
我也没想问你
You and me both.
这事没什么好结果 泰丝
This isn't gonna end well, Tess.
我们得往回走
We need to go back.
让我们把这票干完
Let's just finish it.
她是否真如火萤所说 那不重要
It doesn't matter if she is or she isn't what the Fireflies say.
只要他们坚信她是
If they believe that she is then,
我们就可以得到我们想要的
we get what we want.
如果她抽搐起来
If she so much as twitches.
别这么做
Don't.
好吧
Okay.
行吗？
Okay?
行吧
Okay.
能给我把枪吗？
Can I have a gun?
- 绝对不行 - 不可以
-Absolutely not. -No.
行吧 老天 我朝他们扔他妈的三明治好了
Okay, Jesus. Fine. I'll have to throw a fuckin' sandwich at them.
外面安全
It's clear.
哇哦
Wow.
哈 白天的外城看起来很不一样吧？
Yeah, looks different in the daylight, huh?
我们该走了
We should get movin'.
看起来像是月球搞得一团糟的样子
It's like a fucked-up moon.
这是被他们炸的？
Is this where they bombed?
没错
Yeah.
大多数大城市都被这么炸了
They hit most of the big cities like this.
他们得想办法阻止疫情蔓延
They had to slow the spread somehow.
这招在波士顿成功了 但在大多数地方都失败了
Worked here, but it didn't in most places.
瞧 往前走就是州议会大厦
So, the State House is across there.
如果直走 大概10分钟路程
It's about a 10-minute walk if you could go straight.
那么？
So?
选远路还是近路？
Long way or short way?
恐怕是选远路 还是选那条“我们他妈死定了”的路
I mean, it's the long way or the "we're fuckin' dead" way.
考虑到这条含糊的信息 我给远路投一票
Well, I vote long way just based on that limited information.
我们得先去酒店那看看
We have to check it from the hotel first.
好
Okay.
那些玩意儿究竟在哪？
Where the fuck are they already?
当他们靠近时 你会注意到的
You'll know it when they're close.
上次我就没发现
I didn't know last time.
你怎么被咬的？
How did you get bit?
隔离区有个老购物中心 你听说过吗？
You know the old mall in the QZ?
你说的是上了锁 封了门
The one that's sealed off and boarded up,
根本不让进的那个？
and no one's supposed to go in, ever?
就是那地方吗？
That one?
随便吧 反正我溜进去了
Whatever. I snuck in.
想看看里边是什么样子
Wanted to see what it was like.
没想到那儿还有东西
Didn't think there was gonna be anything in there,
有个家伙不知从哪儿窜出来冲向我
and then one just came at me outta nowhere.
我以为自己安全了 没想到
Thought I got away, but.
你去的时候就你自己？
So it was just you in there, alone?
对
Yeah.
你多大了？
How old are you?
十四岁
Fourteen.
哇
Wow.
我想说 你还挺有胆量的 小妹妹
Well, I mean, you got some balls on you, sister.
谢了
Thanks.
没人来找你吧？
Nobody's gonna be comin' after you, right?
比方说 你妈妈
Like, Mom,
爸爸
Dad,
男朋友？
boyfriend?
我是个孤儿
I'm an orphan,
而且 也没男朋友
and, no.
每个人都跟我说 外城很可怕
Everyone said the open city was crazy.
差不多就是 成群结队的感染者随处可见
Like, swarms of Infected running around everywhere.
不完全是那样
Not exactly like that.
人们喜欢讲故事 你懂的
You know, people like to tell stories.
也就是说 没有什么超级感染者往你身上炸真菌孢子？
So, there aren't Super-Infected that explode fungus spores on you?
操 我倒希望不会有
Shit, I hope not.
那 有没有脑袋裂开的那种？跟蝙蝠似的 在黑暗中也能看见
Or ones with split-open heads that see in the dark like bats?
什么声音？
What was that?
继续往前走吧
Let's keep movin'.
开什么玩笑！
You've gotta be kidding me!
你俩曾经住过这地方？
Ya ever stay in a place like this?
不 这儿太高级了
No, a little out of our league.
你怎么知道这里是干嘛的？
How do you even know what this is?
你难道没有听过书这种东西吗？
Have you heard of books?
等等 我们要下水？
Wait, are we going in there?
对 得去另一侧的楼梯井
Yeah, we gotta get to the stairwell on the other side.
呃 我不会游泳
Well, I don't know how to swim.
真的假的？
Seriously?
你觉得咱们那隔离区里会有游泳池？
Do you think we have pools in the QZ?
聪明死你
No, smart ass.
我是说
I mean.
我怎么可能知道
I don't know how I was supposed to know that.
太恶心了
This is so gross.
快来看！
Check it out!
叮 叮
Ding, ding.
是的先生 我要你们最好的套房 谢谢
Yes, sir. I would like your finest suite, please.
好的女士 需要我为您提行李吗？
Yes, ma'am. Would you like me to take your luggage?
好的女士 马上来 女士——
Yes, ma'am. Right away, ma'am--
你真是个怪小孩
You're a weird kid.
你才是怪小孩
我操！
Oh fuck!
我的天
Oh, my God.
不好意思
Sorry.
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事 好他妈极了
Yep. Fucking fabulous.
操 要人命了
Fuck. Holy shit.
得了 没那么糟吧
Come on, it wasn't that bad.
你用我们的膝盖爬他妈十层试试
You try climbing ten fuckin' floors with our knees.
看看你啥感觉
See how ya feel.
这他妈啥时候变这样了？
Well, when the fuck did that happen?
没准那扇能行
Maybe that one.
不行
No.
行吧 我觉着 也许我可以爬上去
All right, well, I mean, maybe I could climb up there,
探探路 然后从里边开门？
work my way around, and open it from the inside?
别 我个子最小 所以我爬过去最容易
No, well, I'm the smallest, so it'd be easier for me to get through.
你要死了我们就白忙活了 你留下来
But you die and we get nothing. You stay.
来帮我一把？
Can you give me a hand?
上边没问题吧？
You good up there?
没问题 但有点乱 我可能需要几分钟
Yeah, it's a bit of a mess, so I'm gonna need a few minutes.
好刀
Nice knife.
这招你哪儿学的？
Where'd you learn to do that?
马戏团呀
The circus.
你是哪里人？
Where are you from?
德克萨斯
Texas.
泰丝呢？
What about Tess?
底特律 在密歇根州
Detroit. It's in Michigan.
我上过学 我知道底特律在哪儿
I go to school. I know where Detroit is.
所以 你俩是——
So, you two like a--
过
Pass.
你是怎么到波士顿来的？
How'd you end up in Boston?
过
Pass.
别再问我的事了
No more questions about me.
感染者能活多久？
How long do Infected live?
我还以为你上过学呢
I thought you went to school.
我那学校傻逼得很
It's a really shitty one.
有的能活一两个月
Well, some last about a month or two.
但也有游荡了20年左右的
But there's others been walkin' around 'bout 20 years.
你杀过吗？
Ever kill one?
嗯 我杀过很多
Yeah, I killed lots of 'em.
难下手吗？
Was it hard?
毕竟 你会想 他们曾经是人
Like, knowing they were people once?
有时候吧
Sometimes.
昨晚那个人呢？
What about that guy last night?
把枪放下 乔尔
Put the gun down, Joel.
现在怎么办？
What now?
居然这么多
There's so many.
上次我们来这儿 它们还在大楼内部深处
The last time we were here, they were still deep inside the buildings.
我猜后来跑来找隔离区的人太多了
Then I guess enough people came through looking for the QZ,
他们进到大楼里 找地方躲着
they went inside seeking shelter,
于是感染者一点一点 一年一年地蚕食掉这座城市
and that's how they get more and more of the city bit by bit, year after year.
它们彼此相连
They're connected.
程度比你以为得更紧密
More than you know.
真菌也生长在地下
The fungus also grows underground.
像电线一样长的纤维 有的能延伸到一英里外
Long fibers like wires, some of them stretching over a mile.
你要是踩到了一个地方的线虫草菌
Now, you step on a patch of cordyceps in one place,
也许就能唤醒别处十几个感染者
and you can wake a dozen Infected from somewhere else.
它们知道了你的位置 就都过来了
Now they know where you are, now they come.
你的免疫能力可挡不住他们把你大卸八块
You're not immune from being ripped apart.
你明白吗？
You understand?
这很重要
It's important.
我在教你保命
I'm tryin' to keep you alive.
所以我们不走那边
So we're not goin' that way.
对
No.
那我们怎么办？
What do we do then?
走近路？
Short way?
走博物馆
Museum.
你他妈是在开玩笑吧
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
楼顶有条路能过去
Well, there's a way across from the top floor.
好啊 你们说行就行
Well, then I guess it's fine.
这条路我们常走
We used to take it all the time.
行
Okay.
听着 这路没问题
Look, it was fine.
好极了
Awesome.
干透了
It's bone dry.
可能里边的都死光了
It could mean they're all finally dead in there.
不是吧
Oh, man.
玛琳给你带了这个吗
Marlene pack you one of these
还是只装了三明治？
or just sandwiches?
带了
Yeah.
好了 还有几条规矩
Okay, so, more ground rules.
我们动作要慢
We're gonna go slowly.
如果我们遇着了什么东西 你躲在我们身后
If we come up against anything, you get behind us
在原地待好 行吗？
and ya stay there, okay?
知道了
Yes.
我空出来了一只手
I have a spare hand.
恭喜你啊
Congratulations.
波士顿博物馆
欢迎您
出
口
波士顿博物馆
礼品店
营业中
欢迎
没错 死透了
Yeah, cooked.
总算有点狗屎运
Finally, some fuckin' luck.
早知道我们一开始就走这边了
I guess we should've gone this way in the first place.
我操！
Oh shit!
这他妈什么东西干的？
What the fuck did that?
可能
Maybe,
可能他在外面受的袭击 然后爬进门里
maybe he was attacked outside, and crawled through the doors.
门是开的 也许就是他
The door was open. Could've been him.
我什么都没听到
I don't hear anything.
会听到什么？
Who would you hear?
你是说这是感染者干的？
Are you saying an Infected did that?
我被感染者袭击过 但不是这样的
Because I've been attacked by one and it wasn't like that.
好了 从现在开始 我们要完全无声
Okay, from this point forward, we are silent.
不是安静 完全无声
Not quiet. Silent.
什么——
What--
别 别问问题 只管照做
No. No questions. Just do it.
独立展厅
它们看不见 但能听到
They can't see, but they can hear.
快跑！
Run!
跑 快跑！
Run, run!
你没事吧？
You all right?
脚踝扭了 但问题不大
Twisted ankle, but, yeah.
你没事吧？
You all right?
这个嘛 我没尿裤子 所以 还行
Well, I didn't shit my pants, so.
这他妈逗我吗？
You fucking kidding me?
如果咱仨里非得有个人被咬 那就这样吧
I mean, if it was gonna happen to one of us.
嘿
Hey,
咱快他妈离开这儿吧
let's get the fuck outta here.
缠你胳膊上
Put this around your arm.
谢了
Thanks.
走过去？
Over there?
对的 我知道 看着挺吓人
Yeah, I know. It looks scary.
刚刚才叫吓人 这是块木板而已
That was scary. This is wood.
在那儿等着 等我们一会儿
Just wait there. Give us a minute.
前边估计还有更多
There's probably more ahead.
那我们到时候再处理
So, we'll deal with it then.
我来吧 我来
I got it. I got it.
那小孩怎么办？
What about the kid?
我是说 也许第一次被咬没感染
I mean, maybe the first bite didn't take,
那这第二次呢？
but what about the second?
你就不能看着点好？
How 'bout you just take the good news?
行吗？
Can you do that?
这次你就不能好好想想 我们或许真有机会成功？
Like to think, for once, maybe we could actually win?
过去吧 过去看着她
Just go, go and watch her.
这一切都如你所愿吗？
Is it everything you hoped for?
还不好说
Jury's still out.
但老兄 这景色绝了
But, man, you can't deny that view.
来吧 咱得在天黑之前到
C'mon, let's get there before it's dark.
他们他妈在哪儿呢？
Where the fuck are they?
待着别动
Stay back.
乔尔？
Joel?
这他妈怎么回事？
What the fuck is going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们进去了
They went inside.
- 来吧 - 泰丝
-Come on. -Tess.
来吧！
Come on!
泰丝！
Tess!
我操
Holy shit.
天啊
Jesus.
好了
Okay.
我说 这儿肯定有他妈的收音机之类的 对吧？
I mean, there's gotta be a fuckin' radio or somethin', right?
谁杀了他们？FEDRA的人？
Who killed them? FEDRA?
不对
No.
他们当中有人被咬了
One of them got bit.
健康的跟病了的打了起来 所有人都输了
The healthy ones fought the sick ones. Everyone lost.
泰丝？你在干嘛？
Tess? What're you doin'?
玛琳说要带你到哪儿去？
Where did Marlene say that she was taking you?
艾莉！
Ellie!
我不知道 只说在西边
I don't know. Just west.
就是西边 他妈的 行吧
Just west. Fuck. Okay.
行 我是说 他们中间肯定有人身上有地图 对吧？
Well, I mean, one of them's gotta have a map on them, right?
乔尔 你能帮把手吗？
Joel, can ya help me?
不能！
No!
泰丝 结束了
Tess, it's over.
我们现在回家
We are going home.
那他妈不是我的家！
That's not my fucking home!
我要留下来
I'm stayin'.
我是说 我们的好运迟早会用完
I mean, our luck had to run out sooner or later.
操
Fuck.
她被感染了
She's infected.
让我看一下
Show me.
乔尔
Joel.
真惨 对吧？
Oops, right?
把你的绷带取下来
Take your bandage off.
乔尔
Look.
看见了么？
Joel?
这是真的
This is real.
乔尔 她是真他妈的免疫
Joel, she's fucking real.
我要你把她送到比尔和弗兰克那儿去
I need you to get her to Bill and Frank's.
- 不行 - 他们会从你那儿接手她
-No. -They'll take her off your hands.
- 不行 - 之后他们来操心
-No. -They'll handle it from here.
不 不 不 不行 他们不会接手的
No, no, no, I can't. They won't take her.
他们不会接收她的
They're not gonna take her.
他们会 因为你会说服他们
They will 'cause you'll convince them.
你会的
Yes, you will.
我从没有要求过你什么
I never ask you for anything,
- 没要你回馈感情 - 不行
-not to feel the way I felt. -No.
把嘴他妈闭上 因为我没时间了
Shut the fuck up 'cause I don't have time.
这是你的机会
This is your chance.
你送她过去
You get her there,
你保她活命
you keep her alive,
你就能重回正道
and you set everything right.
我们可是做过了那么多破事
All the shit we did.
拜托你答应 乔尔 求你了
Please say yes, Joel, please.
我操！
Oh fuck!
有多少？
How many?
全都来了
All of them.
顶多一分钟到
Maybe a minute.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
确保他们追不上你们
Making sure that they don't follow you.
乔尔
Joel.
救你能救的人
Save who you can save.
不！
No!
我们不能丢下她！
We're not leaving her!
放开我 你个混蛋！
Get off me, you fucker!
我不要跟你走！
I'm not going with you!
关注衣柜字幕组
小红书 微信公众号 西瓜视频@衣柜军团
微博 B站@衣柜军团发声筒
译制人员
北落微博@北落不会呀 B站@北落yubekyu
疾火微博@疾火_凡庸之火将把所有高贵屠戮 B站@尘蕊蝶